export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2023 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A group of people in a theatre being entertained by actors is",
A: "allonym.",
B: "audience.",
C: "cast.",
D: "chorus.",
answer: "B. audience",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A book which contains poems written by different poets is",
A: "anthology.",
B: "apogee.",
C: "cacophony.",
D: "collection.",
answer: "A. anthology",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A short story which involves human beings and teaches a lesson is",
A: "an allegory.",
B: "an allusion.",
C: "a parable.",
D: "a satire.",
answer: "C. a parable",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. I have read Chinua Achebe is an example of",
A: "litotes.",
B: "metonymy.",
C: "paradox.",
D: "parody.",
answer: "B. metonymy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. In drama, a script",
A: "suggests the time and place of the drama.",
B: "is a set of bracketed information.",
C: "suggests where movies are produced.",
D: "is the written form of drama.",
answer: "D. is the written form of drama",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Anunexpected deviation in writing from a serious issue to something unimportant is",
A: "allusion.",
B: "bathos.",
C: "fantasy.",
D: "pathos.",
answer: "B. bathos",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The underlined expression illustrates",
A: "apostrophe.",
B: "euphemism.",
C: "hyperbole.",
D: "litotes.",
answer: "D. litotes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The expres is",
A: "an rtion that Ben is married.",
B: "a denial that Ben is married.",
C: "an invitation to May to stay with Ben.",
D: "a proposal to May to marry Ben.",
answer: "A. an assertion that Ben is married",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The Petrarchan sonnet comprises",
A: "a couplet and a quatrain.",
B: "an octave and a sestet.",
C: "a sestet and a couplet.",
D: "an octave and a quatrain",
answer: "B. an octave and a sestet",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The underlined expression illustrates",
A: "alliteration.",
B: "assonance.",
C: "contrast.",
D: "parallelism.",
answer: "A. alliteration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The literary device in the second line is",
A: "bathos.",
B: "conceit.",
C: "inversion.",
D: "metre.",
answer: "C. inversion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The last two lines illustrate",
A: "epithet.",
B: "pathos.",
C: "simile.",
D: "zeugina.",
answer: "B. pathos",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A dramatic performance with only bodily movement is called",
A: "aside.",
B: "mime.",
C: "opera.",
D: "soliloquy",
answer: "B. mime",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. I am so th 1 can drink a barrel of water illustrates",
A: "hyperbole",
B: "irony.",
C: "metaphor.",
D: "sarcasm.",
answer: "A. hyperbole",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The literary device used to highlight the ills of society for their correction is",
A: "relief.",
B: "dramatic irony.",
C: "satire.",
D: "suspense.",
answer: "C. satire",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A short, witty statement in a literary work is an",
A: "elegy.",
B: "epigram.",
C: "epitaph.",
D: "innuendo.",
answer: "B. epigram",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The above poem is an example of",
A: "a concrete poem.",
B: "an elegy.",
C: "a pastoral poem.",
D: "an ode.",
answer: "A. a concrete poem",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The underlined words are an example of",
A: "alliteration.",
B: "onomatopoeia.",
C: "pun.",
D: "rhyme.",
answer: "D. rhyme",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A struggle between opposing forces ina story or a play is",
A: "conflict.",
B: "denouement.",
C: "hubris.",
D: "tragedy.",
answer: "A. conflict",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A drama curtain parts or at the beginning and closes or ..... at the end of an act or a drama.",
A: "falls; rises",
B: "rises; rises",
C: "falls; falls",
D: "rises; falls",
answer: "D. rises; falls",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The passage is about",
A: "a greedy man.",
B: "strange encounter.",
C: "the setting sun.",
D: "the visit of a lover.",
answer: "B. strange encounter",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The lady is described as",
A: "amazing.",
B: "dazzling.",
C: "lustful.",
D: "nonchalant.",
answer: "B. dazzling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The narrator’s mood changes from one of expectation to that of",
A: "anxiety.",
B: "disappointment.",
C: "excitement.",
D: "sadness.",
answer: "D. sadness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The passage ends in",
A: "an allusion.",
B: "an anecdote.",
C: "a conceit.",
D: "a pun.",
answer: "B. an anecdote",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. *******************************",
A: "an allusion.",
B: "an anecdote.",
C: "a conceit.",
D: "a pun.",
answer: "D. a pun",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The poem is about",
A: "fishing expedition.",
B: "rowing.",
C: "sea voyage..",
D: "yachting.",
answer: "A. fishing expedition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which line clearly expresses what the poem is about?",
A: "ten conspirational men in their boats",
B: "lines, sinkers and hooks prepared",
C: "rested their ribs on the gunwales",
D: "for a change in the tide",
answer: "B. lines, sinkers and hooks prepared",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. poor prey refers to",
A: "birds.",
B: "fishes.",
C: "gunwales.",
D: "sinkers.",
answer: "B. fishes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The mood of the persona is",
A: "antagonistic.",
B: "empathetic.",
C: "flippant.",
D: "serious.",
answer: "D. serious",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. .. patient oars ...\nrested their ribs ... illustrates",
A: "allusion and transferred epithet.",
B: "personification and allusion.",
C: "transferred epithet and personification.",
D: "personification and onomatopoeia.",
answer: "C. transferred epithet and personification",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Quince has just assigned the part of the lion to",
A: "Flute.",
B: "Puck.",
C: "Snug.",
D: "Starveling.",
answer: "C. Snug",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The player of the lion’s part is told to",
A: "accept another part.",
B: "be punctual at rehearsals.",
C: "play the part extempore.",
D: "take the written script.",
answer: "D. take the written script",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Bottom says Let me play the lion too because, already, he is to play the part",
A: "Pyramus.",
B: "Pyramus’s father.",
C: "Thisby.",
D: "' Thisby’s father.",
answer: "A. Pyramus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Quince",
A: "gives in to Bottom.",
B: "insists that Bottom play his original part.",
C: "next gives Snug his part.",
D: "urges Starveling to play his part extempore.",
answer: "B. insists that Bottom play his original part",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Speaker X is",
A: "all the players together.",
B: "one of the players.",
C: "Flute.",
D: "Snug.",
answer: "A. all the players together",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker is",
A: "Bottom.",
B: "Oberon.",
C: "Peaseblossom",
D: "Puck.",
answer: "B. Oberon",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The addressee is",
A: "Fairy.",
B: "Flute.",
C: "Titania.",
D: "Snug.",
answer: "C. Titania",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. she in the extract refers to",
A: "Helena.",
B: "Hermia.",
C: "Hippolyta.",
D: "Titania.",
answer: "D. Titania",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. they in the extract refers to",
A: "Demetrius and Helena.",
B: "Hermia and Lysander.",
C: "Oberon and Titania.",
D: "Theseus and Hippolyta.",
answer: "C. Oberon and Titania",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The setting is",
A: "wood.",
B: "Egeus’s house.",
C: "the palace.",
D: "Quince’s house.",
answer: "A. wood",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The speaker is",
A: "Demetrius.",
B: "Oberon.",
C: "Puck.",
D: "Titania.",
answer: "D. Titania",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The speaker is addressing",
A: "Bottom.",
B: "Hermia.",
C: "Oberon.",
D: "Peaseblossom",
answer: "A. Bottom",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The speaker and the addressee are",
A: "Amazons.",
B: "Athenians.",
C: "in love.",
D: "in shock.",
answer: "C. in love",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Before the speech, the speaker has",
A: "quatreled with a partner.",
B: "woken from a sleep.",
C: "worn an ass’s head.",
D: "saved a boy.",
answer: "B. woken from a sleep",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The scene is",
A: "a room in Egeus’s house.",
B: "a room in Quince’s house.",
C: "the palace.",
D: "the wood.",
answer: "D. the wood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Speaker X is",
A: "Bottom.",
B: "Quince.",
C: "Snout.",
D: "Starvelling.",
answer: "B. Quince",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Speaker Y is",
A: "Flute.",
B: "Lysander",
C: "Snug.",
D: "Theseus.",
answer: "A. Flute",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. He in the extract is",
A: "Bottom.",
B: "Lysander.",
C: "Starvelling.",
D: "Theseus.",
answer: "A. Bottom",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The scene is",
A: "a room in the palace.",
B: "another part of the wood.",
C: "a room in Quince’s house",
D: "the wood.",
answer: "B. another part of the wood",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The person not heard of",
A: "has committed suicide.",
B: "has eloped.",
C: "is missing.",
D: "is newly married.",
answer: "C. is missing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]